<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Css | Morry's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/categories/css/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-16T16:23:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sparkmorry.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mengli Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Css More Efficiently]]></title>
    <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/2014/02/16/how-to-use-css-more-efficient/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-16T13:00:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/2014/02/16/how-to-use-css-more-efficient</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;It all starts from a <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1875852/define-colors-as-variables-in-css">question</a> on stackoverflow. I have been working on the website <a href="http://www.weixinfr.com/">weixinfr</a> these days, as we haven&rsquo;t decided the main color style yet, it troubles me repeatedly changing from color to color. For instance, I use red as the color of active link, some titles, the background color of buttons and some selectors. But what if I want to change the color style to green next time? Should I find all the &ldquo;red&rdquo;(or #whatever) keyword in the text and determine on each fragment if it is the one to change?</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Color, font, positioning are the main functions of css, I used to define all of them on a certeain box, like:</p>

<p>for box1:</p>

<pre><code>#nav-wrapper{
    position:fixed;  //positioning
    height: 60px;
    z-index: 60;
    width: 100%;
    padding: 0;
    margin:0;
    text-align: center;   //for text
    background-color: #fff;    //bg-color
    color: red;
    border-bottom: solid 1px #ececec;     //color
}
</code></pre>

<p>for box2, repeatedly:</p>

<pre><code>#login-form{
    text-align: left;
    color: white;
    position: absolute;
    top: 70px;
    right: 80px; 
    z-index: 80;
    display: block;
    background-color: rgba(0,0,0,0.4); 
    padding: 20px 35px;
}
</code></pre>

<p>so everytime I am going to change, I have to check every box to change the color. The idea comes into my mind that how can I use a variable to store the number of the color, and put it somewhere I use it? I know something like <a href="http://lesscss.org/">less</a> makes it possible, but I also want some css solutions. Some anwsers on stackoverflow really inspires me. Colour reference chart, CSS3 variables, sass/scss, grouping the selectors only on color, and setting up a .red class(or alternative color_style).</p>

<p>Actually, I suppose the idea of the last two are the same: always group up the common style/feature togeter. One of the most exciting things in css is each element can have more than one class. To compare with the 2 solutions, we can still find some differences though. By defining a class called &ldquo;red_text&rdquo;, I have to look up all the elements in the html file to remove or add the class, and once I want to change the color to green, I have to rename it &ldquo;green_text&rdquo; for the readability(or make it deco_text).</p>

<pre><code>.deco_text{color:red;}
</code></pre>

<p> The alternative one makes it a little better, it only deals with the css file. But the trouble is you need to be careful about the selectors.</p>

<pre><code>#section1, #section2 {color:red;}
</code></pre>

<p>There is always no only right answer in my opnion, you should also take the HTML semantics into account. It defers from the authors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
