<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Essay | Morry's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/categories/essay/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T12:24:00+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sparkmorry.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mengli Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress Journey]]></title>
    <link href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/2014/02/12/octopress-journey/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-12T16:42:24+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sparkmorry.github.io/blog/2014/02/12/octopress-journey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;After one-day searching, I finally set up my own blog by octopress. It looks so amazing and I just fall in love with the green markdown at the first glance. I will just imigrate the previous blog <a href="http://www.cnblogs.com/sparkmorry/">http://www.cnblogs.com/sparkmorry/</a> @cnblog here.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This is just a testing post where I learn how to write an article with markdown and post it under a certain page. According to the documentation of Octopress, to write a new post and create a new page:</p>

<pre><code>rake new_page[super-awesome]
# creates /source/super-awesome/index.markdown

rake new_page[super-awesome/page.html]
# creates /source/super-awesome/page.html
</code></pre>

<p>to publish:</p>

<pre><code>rake generate   # Generates posts and pages into the public directory
rake watch      # Watches source/ and sass/ for changes and regenerates
rake preview    # Watches, and mounts a webserver at http://localhost:4000
rake deploy
rake gen_deploy #combination
</code></pre>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I have come across a problem of the blog configuration, the source code should be under the root directory for preview, or maybe by changing somewhere else. I am still in my process of learning this new awsome tool.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Here in my blog, the posts are under <a href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/">Articles</a>. The articles are mainly about the reflections on front-end development and my daily life. Also, you may see some recent work on drawings or photographies under <a href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/painting/">Gallery</a> as I really like both of them. For more infomation, plz see <a href="http://sparkmorry.github.io/about/">About page</a>. Thanks to github and octopress that I can set up the blog for free.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you have any issues or questions on the code or posts, please contact me. Lastly, I&rsquo;m so pleasant of having your visit on this blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
